Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajpur.
I am the founder of Family First Financial
Services. I have an MBA in Finance and have been working
in the corporate sector for 13 years.
Today I am presenting to you
Canara HSBC's Gain Guaranteed Plan,
Guaranteed Income Plan. The full name
of this plan is Guaranteed Income Income Plan.
In short, we can say Gain Plan, which is a
100% guaranteed plan. It is a non-lung, non-
participating plan. Here you are given
excellent different options for short term and long term
income.
Let us understand the plan in detail.
Talking about the features of the policy,
here you will get insurance. Here
you will get the option of regular income. If you
want to take income in increasing order, then the
option of increasing is also given and the
total amount you have deposited will be refunded 100% to you on
policy maturity.
In this policy, you are given three benefit options:
short term income option and
long term income option, plus  The
option of early income is also given.
I will explain these three options in detail. The
eligibility criteria of the policy is
short term and long term.
Here, a
person up to 60 years of age can purchase the policy. The minimum
maturity period of the policy can be
18 years and
you can take this policy up to a maximum of 99 years.
Talking about the premium payment term,
in the short term, you have the option of premium payment of 5 years and 7 years.
Plus, you can
also take a deferment period of zero to 5 years, that is,
you can wait.
After that, if the premium payment term is of 5 years, then
you can take income for 5 years and if the
premium payment term is of 7 years, then you
can take income for 7 years. For example, there is a
person who takes a premium payment
term of 5 years, takes a deferment period of 5 years
and takes an income term of 5 years, then
his total policy term becomes 15 years,
but he wants  Is it true or not, I don't want to wait,
I want income for 7 years, so I will
pay premium for 5 years and will get income for 5 years, the total
policy term will be 10 years, in the same
way you can see, if we talk about
long term income benefit, then here
you will get the option of premium payment for 5 years, 7 years, 10 years and 12 years, there
are many different options for income, here
you can get income for 10 years, 15 years, 20 years, 25 years or
even 30 years, suppose
you paid premium for 12 years, waited for 5 years and
took income for 30 years, then total 5 x 12
+ 30 means your policy term will be 47 years, so
according to your need you have to pay premium for 5 years, if
you wait then you will get more income, if you do
not wait then you can take income from the next year itself after paying the premium, you have to
wait for one year, wait for two years
after that  If you want to take income, you can take it. If you
want to take income after waiting for 5 years,
you can take income for 10 years,
15 years, 20 years, 25 years or 30 years. You
can select any option from these. If you are
selecting the long term option, then regarding the
features of short term and long term option, here you will get insurance cover, you will
get guaranteed income. When will the guaranteed income start
coming? When will you make the premium
payment and if you have taken any deferred policy, then
after that you will start getting income.
You can take the income in monthly mode,
semi-annually, quarterly or yearly mode.
You
can take the start up income option here. From 5 onwards, your
income will come in increasing order every year, so this
option is also optional, if you
want to, you can take this option also.
Here you will get back your entire 100% money
on maturity and
you will also get tax benefit in income tax
if you choose the option short term.  Are you taking a short term policy
or a long term policy,
what will you get if you die? You will get the sum assured death.
What will you get on maturity? The
total amount that you have
paid as premium will be given to you on maturity.
What will you get on survival benefit?
You get income every year, that is the
assured income plus any loyalty income
if the company has given it, then both of these together are
given to you as income every year,
which is called survival benefit. The eligibility criteria for
early income of option number three is
that here
also a person from zero to 60 years
can purchase the policy. The minimum
maturity age is 18 years and the maximum
maturity age is 99 years.
Here you have been given only two options of 10 years and 12 years. The
policy term option of 30 years
or 40 years has been given. Here
you will start getting income from the second year onwards from the second year of making the premium.
Suppose you have  If you have purchased the policy in 2024,
you have to wait for one year. For 2025,
you will start getting income from 2026 and this
income can take you for the next 30 or 40 years.
Suppose you have taken the 40 year option, then you have to wait for 1 year, that is,
you will get guaranteed income till the age of 39,
plus
you will get refund of the money deposited at maturity.
Insurance cover is the benefit of early income option, you will also get guaranteed
income in this option, the
payout of income will be from the second year. From the second year,
you also have the option of immediate income and
after completion of the premium payment term, you will
also get assured income in this policy, plus
loyalty income is also given, you can
take it in monthly, quarterly, semi-annual or annual mode, whichever mode you want to take income in. You will get tax benefit
in this also and
you will get back the entire 100% money deposited at maturity. Now let us
understand.  Canara HSBC Guaranteed
Income Plan with benefit illustration:
For example, a 35-year-old man purchases a
policy, paying premium for 12 years.
He takes a 5-year deferred period and
selects income for 10 years, meaning
he wants income for 10 years,
for which he is paying Rs 1 lakh as annual
premium. Here, he has not opted for the start-up income option. He is
paying the premium in annual mode. The
insurance cover will be 11 times. The
option he has taken here is for long-term income.
Here, you will get an assured income
of Rs 0.030, loyalty income is Rs 815, and the
total income will be Rs
2445. Let us calculate it this way:
you have paid Rs 1 lakh as premium for 12 years,
then you have waited for 5 years, you have
taken a deferred period of 5 years, then for the next 10 years, you have  If you have
selected to take income, then here you will
see that above 160000 it is written assured
income or stand up income. Loyal income will also
come to you separately, so 030 p.m. 0000 total.
You will get
2445 guaranteed income for the next 10 years
and later whatever you have paid in total in 12 years,
that too will be given to you as maturity.
This is the maturity benefit
and all the benefits will be guaranteed to you.
Your insurance cover will be 11 times of 11 lakhs
and it will increase up to 126 lakhs in a little time. There is
no surrender benefit in the first year,
after that you also start getting surrender benefit here.
You can also take a loan till 80 years of age on surrender benefit. This
income of 240000 will give you tax free
income and the match will also be tax free. Let's
try another option also and see
how it works. Here
I have tried this for 35 years.  There is an option to pay premium for 12 years. There is a
waiting period of only two years.
And this time, instead of 10 years, the income has been
selected to be taken for 30 years. So,
this policy will be valid for a total of 44 years.
You have paid Rs. 1 lakh each for 12 years.
After that, you will start getting assured income and loyalty income. Rs.
9760, Rs.
45380, Rs.
13610 will be guaranteed for the next 30 years
and later you will get back the paid Rs. 1 lakh on
maturity. Insurance cover will
also be there. The option of surrender benefit is also
given here. So finally, let us look at the
option of early income. Let us look at the
way it works. If you are a 35-year-old person, after
purchasing the policy, you are paying premium for 12 years
and are using the early income option, then that
means, you will get income till the age of 39. You are
paying an annual premium of Rs. 1 lakh. The
option that has been taken is the early income option.  So let us
see,
here you have paid one lakh for 12 years,
how much immediate income are you
getting here, from the second year when does the income of 0000 ad
start, when the premium payment is complete,
you will
start getting 8160 ad income plus
loyalty income of ₹ 480 for you, so by
adding
10240 here, till the time you pay the premium, the
income is 0000, after the premium payment is complete, you will get an
income of 10240 and later
you will get back the 12 lakhs that you have paid, the insurance
cover will also be there from day one, in this way
you can understand this plan from the benefit illustration,
talk about other benefits and
features of the policy, in this policy if you have
paid only one premium and do not pay it, then the policy will lapse, if
minimum two premiums
are due then you can get it RPU done, there is a
loan facility in the policy, here you will get
surrender benefit at 80%
You can take a loan up to 80% of the surrender value.
You will get tax benefit under Section AC of Income Tax and
tax-free income under Section 10AD. The
free premium in this policy will be for 15 days
and the revival premium will be for
5 years. Suppose, if for some reason you are
not able to pay the premium on time, then
you can revive this policy within 5 years by paying the premium for the remaining years together. The
policy will be continued.
I have explained the surrender benefit to you in detail in the benefit illustration. So
finally, if
I were to review this plan, it is a good
plan. It is a 100% guaranteed plan. There are tax
benefits. Many different premium
payment term options are given.
Different policy term options are given. If
you want to earn income quickly, you
can take short-term income. If you want to earn income for a long time, then the
long-term income option is given. If you
want to earn immediate income and
want to earn income from the second year, then  That option has
also been given to you in the policy, so keeping your
needs in mind there are many
options, you can select any option from these according to your need,
you can also select the premium payment term and policy term as per
your need,
if you like the video then you will already find
more than 3 videos
related to insurance on my YouTube which will
help you in your financial planning, if
you want to purchase this policy from me
then you can call me
on 9940 3412, Jai Hind